So, dear gentlemen, and women, let's keep going with the second phase of this
lesson,
which is research.
So research is probably the most important phase of the entire strategy,
because in the
research we'll define whether you will make successful investments with
successful returns.
Everything lies here on the research phase, and your ability to pick and choose
influencers
will be developed in this specific phase, how to find high-performing influ
encers, how
to measure the risk of them.
So, let's keep going.
The first lesson that I want to teach you guys is that there is two categories
in terms
of research.
Celebrities, it's one category.
We at HappyFlops call them icons, and I will explain to you why.
Second category, this is the first, is high-performing influencers.
This is the second category, and they are different, and I will explain to you
how they
differentiate and who you should pick depending on what phase.
I actually even wrote this down here.
Celebrities, you should only do if you are already an established brand, and I
will explain
to you a little bit why.
The second is high-performing influencers.
Happy-forming influencers is a little bit more adapted to smaller brands, and I
will also
explain to you why.
If, however, you are on the established brand category, you can do both, which,
for example,
is what we do at HappyFlops.
We invest both in celebrities, but also in high-performing influencers.
Now, budget-wise, there is, of course, a difference.
This could cost everything from $30,000 to $50,000 up to $500,000 for one call-
up.
This is an extremely expensive strategy, but it also comes with insanely
returns.
Meanwhile, high-performing influencers, so this is for this, high-performing
influencers
could cost everything from $5,000 up to probably $30,000 USD.
And both could generate very, very high return if you know how to choose them.
So this is very important, because you might invest $30, $50,000, $500 in one
celebrity
and they will give you zero return, the same with high-performing influencers.
You could invest $5,000 up to $30,000, and you will get maybe not exactly zero
return,
but you will have loss, 100% loss on your investment, right?
This is why a lot of brands doesn't dare to do this, because you're basically
betting
$30,000 or $10,000 in one person, which for a lot of people or for a lot of
brands is
a lot of money, too high risk, right?
So that's why this chapter is about how to measure risk, how to measure trust,
all right?
All right, guys, so let's continue.
How could we define and identify celebrities worth investing in?
So this is a checklist.
Now you don't see the checking icon, but I will do this, check, check, check,
check,
all right?
If the celebrity check all these boxes, hey, my man, invest, invest, invest
because the
return will be beyond your wildest imaginations.
First of all, celebrity, why do we call them for icons?
You know why?
Because that's basically what the celebrities that we invested are, they are
iconic figures.
So what is an iconic figure?
Hey, after a lot of tests and after a lot of failures, we actually understood
what it
is.
And I will tell you one story, all right, one story to highlight what kind of
celebrity
you should not invest in.
And I will explain through these points which celebrities you should invest in.
Here, yes, oops.
All right, so first of all, let's begin with this part of yes.
What is an iconic figure?
Iconic figure is a personal individual that the whole country knows about, all
right?
How do we test this?
We actually do this.
We go on the street and we ask 10 people about this person, 9 out of 10 people,
almost
un-undependently on which age you are asking, they know this person, all right?
This is an iconic figure.
It doesn't matter if you ask a 25-year-old person, a 45-year-old person, both
will tell
you that yes, they know this.
If you go on the street randomly and ask, hey, do you know about this person?
If 9 out of 10 people say yes in different ages, then you know you're into
something,
all right?
The next, respect, admiration, and likable.
How can you know if a famous person is respected, admired, or likable?
When you go out on the street and you ask about this person, you will see a
reaction.
So a lot of people, famous people are famous, but necessarily not respected,
necessarily
not admired, and necessarily not likable.
And this is very logical and also very basic, but also this is the difference
between making
a lot of money or not making anything.
You need to define this.
So the reaction of the people you're asking on the street will give you the
answer.
If the reaction is, oh, yes, I know this person, and they are happy, which
means they like
the person, and then you can continue to ask, why do you know this person and
why do you
like this person?
If the answer has anything to do with admiration and respect, man, you can
check the box.
Because all of the celebrities that we work with has these metrics that are
checking.
And trust me, it's not that easy to find either, because there are so many
famous people that,
by the way, we've also invested in that just have not this respect and
admiration.
This just have fame, because they are famous for entertainment, all right?
So we don't want to invest in entertainment.
We want to invest in this respect, admiration and likeable, all right?
Next thing, reputation.
What are they famous for?
So, so important.
I will tell you an example where you should avoid, all right?
Do you all know about programs like Paradise Hotel, for example, or X on the
beach, all
right?
Or some programs that are similar, it's drama shows, basically drama shows that
are very
popular on TV for a lot of people.
In Love Island, I would say.
And a lot of these people that win these programs, they get awarded and so on.
They get pretty much famous after this.
And a lot of brands try to keep up with the trend, and they start to invest in
these people
for everything.
They invite them to restaurants, they sell them to promote products.
And you know what happens always with these profiles because I've done the same
zero sales.
You know why?
Because people watch them and they are famous for entertainment.
They are people that entertain you, they make you love, they make you maybe
even cry.
I don't know, they entertain you, but they are not there to lift up human
feelings such
as respect, admiration, and likable, maybe likable in some cases for these
programs.
But yeah, so what is the reputation for?
Are they famous for these kinds of programs or are they famous for something
else?
For example, the people that we work with, they are famous because of fame
positive.
I will call this charity work, for example.
It's a very common actually reputation they have that they are connected to
some kind
of charity work.
It doesn't always mean that they are working with the organization for example
with poor
people.
But a lot of these people that are iconic is helping in some way to the country
.
For example, for kids, for cancer, for all the kind of sickness or diseases,
there are
sometimes or a lot of times invited to talk about society, about education,
about kids.
This means pretty much that they are involved to actually grow the nation, grow
people, grow
society.
That's the reputation.
What are they famous for?
Not this entertainment, but something that is admirable or respected.
This needs to also check the box.
In the end of the day, this is what creates trust.
Trust and loyalty from local people.
How do we get to know this for sure?
I will demonstrate this in a second step very soon.
How you can find how much trust this celebrities has from people.
This needs to check the boxes.
This is the category.
Let's go to the other side, high performing influences.
What is the difference?
What is the difference between high performing influencers and celebrities?
First of all, high performing influencers is not nationally known.
Not nationally the same.
High performing influencers are dependent on their follower base basically, but
the power
of the relationship with this follower base.
Power of this follower base.
Which basically means their relationship.
This is what we define the strength of these high performing influencers.
What do we look for here?
We already spoke a little bit about authority.
People that have channels with some kind of authority, but what is it?
The other things that we need to check the box to define them as a high
performing influencer.
Now we're coming to the really neat and greedy stuff.
First of all, the first lesson you should identify in a high performing influ
encer is
this daily story content with talking on camera.
Hey guys, I have spelled beans now.
This is probably, I was putting a major factor here, guys, listen to this very
carefully.
And I will obviously show this, look, all the influencers that has this daily
content
story talking on camera is equal to these millions.
Of you is the, and I will explain to you why, I will explain to you why.
Second thing you need to check the box, average comments, always about 50 or 60
.
And you know why?
Because this means that the influencer is very engaged with the audience.
They are answering the comments, they are putting some questions, they are
starting conversations,
you know, this, what this means, it means that they fucking care.
This means relationship, relation, this means bonding, this means the
connection, what I
said.
So you need to look for people or an influencer that is, that are engaging with
their audiences.
And there's very particular methods that they do this, which I will actually
show you in
a bit, looking on different influencers as an example.
And this is basically what you need to look for.
And there is very hard to look for this in this AI or this influencer platforms
.
You need to look on this yourself by looking, by searching, by reading.
This is what it means to go the extra fucking mile.
You want results, you want extraordinary things.
You really need to do extraordinary things as well then.
And this is very, very manual work, actually, to find this, to read about this.
But this is what we do and I'm telling you, this is the winning method and the
winning
strategy.
What else is very common for all the high-performing influencers is award
winners.
You can actually Google up which awards it exists in your country for influ
encers, super
nice and super easy way to find already very quick the performing influencers.
Because award winners usually are based on a lot of votes, or votes from a lot
of influencers,
from a lot of people, which means they are voted from the market.
If the market puts you as the number one, it usually means a lot.
And I can almost tell you, in a lot of countries that we've done this, a lot of
the high-performing
influencers, they are always the winners in all the awards in this contest that
it exists
in different countries.
Next thing that I also recommend to identify high-performing influencers for
your brand
is to use the bio from the Instagram, which means a lot of influencers use
their bio to
define what they are doing, for example, mother.
And I will explain to you how you can understand what the bio means and how you
could define
if the influencer is a mother influencer because they are writing mother on
their bio.
This is also very common for high-performing influencers, they are very precise
on what
they write on their bio.
So the difference between this, as you can see, is different because
celebrities are,
for example, not necessarily doing the daily stories, for example, these daily
stories,
they are not doing this average comments, they are not award winners for influ
encer contests.
Of course, you see, there's a lot of differences, but you depend and rely on
these other things.
But both of these, both of them, I would say this, equals extremely high level
of trust.
If you follow these boxes, these boxes, so both, for example, we've invested in
influencers
that has generated equally high revenue as a celebrity.
So both are equally powerful, but they are just, you need to understand the
different
ways how to find them and how to evaluate them, all right?
Good, now we understood that there is two categories, we also understood how to
identify
high-performing influencers and how to define or identify celebrities that are
also high-performing.
Let's move on.
How do we actually create a list?
Let me just remove this so we can focus on the list creation, all right?
So now we're coming into more practical stuff, how do we use platforms and
tools to make
lists that you should evaluate and then later on pick from, pick celebrities
that you will
be investing and remember, now we're coming to the measure, how to measure the
risk, all
right?
First of all, we look at models.
This is the way we create a list and we do AI research.
AI research, by the way, this is really, really exclusive stuff we are sharing
today.
We will share with you a prompt, AI prompt that is the brain of all of our
influencers.
This prompt knows about all of our influencers that has generated us tens of
millions of
dollars.
So this means that you should just add this prompt to your chat JPT or Claude
and then
you can basically just add the Instagram link or name and they will give you a
report about
the likelihood and the measurement of the trust that they believe this person
has and
this especially works with celebrities because in celebrities, it exists so
much information
online.
But that's not all, absolutely not all because this only gives you signals,
right?
You need to, this is the way you measure and lower your risk.
You never take decisions, for example, on the AI report research or only on,
for example,
the metrics and statics from the MODASH platform.
I will explain to you soon what is MODASH and then I will also explain, this is
keywords
that we will use to make a list in MODASH and then local interviews, all right,
look
guys, I will basically now share my screen, go into MODASH and then show you
how we do
a list where our goal is to do a list of 100 people at least or fifth and then
we filter
it down to 50 to 20 and then to 10 and this from this 10 will be the absolute
best and
most analyzed profiles that we will then reach out to, right, you will reach
out to 10 people
based on your whole analyze from 100 and then from 50 and then 20 people.
So first of all, we start with MODASH, MODASH is a platform that looks like
this, all right,
MODASH.io, MODASH.io is one of the platforms that we found the best data, we
tested tens
of platforms for influencers and creators and I can tell you one thing, being a
very,
very good at influencer marketing, MODASH has absolutely the best data to
analyze and
to judge influencers on. All the other platforms, I can tell you straight away
has very poor
poor data. So how do we start if we would launch this in a, for example, UK,
all right,
and we will want to do a celebrity list. First of all, we only will use
actually two features
from this platform, which is first of all location, we put United Kingdom,
right, and
then we use bio and we put TV, perfect.
TV, all right, as you can see on my iPad, I'm not used to do this, but I'm
doing this
for the case of, I'll show you guys. So looking for United Kingdom and for TV
on their bio,
I actually get 1600 profiles, all right. So I put TV host and let's see if it's
changed.
So it's changed completely. Now I have 42 profiles that writes on their bio
that they
are TV hosts, perfect. So what will I do? I will look through all of these
profiles one
by one. And I will look at their statistics from Modash and I will focus on
this specific
task, listen very carefully. First of all, I will have this, for example,
celebrity, open
full report. I will copy her Instagram name, copy link. And then I will go to
my chat
to be bring here, projects, influencers, all right. And then I will add this
link, which
is her Instagram link. Give me an analyze of this profile. And we, as we
usually do,
all right, click. You will get this prompt. So you can do this with any influ
encer from
any country. And this is the way we, you will need to do this with all of these
influencers.
You had 42 influencers on this list. All right. So here you will get a really
nice and very
in-depth analyze where it starts with national awareness. They will explain to
you how she
is nationally known, why she says celebrity, like ability, as we spoke about,
it's a very,
very important factor. We have human connection, which means if you remember,
does people believe
that they know this person, right? It's not only famous because of
entertainment or whatever.
Do people believe that they know them because they have been seeing this person
talking so
much that they understand her personality? That creates trust, all right? Human
connection.
Chad will explain to you why it's 8 out of 8.5 out of 10. A family fits, in
this case,
for our band, for example, we are reaching out to families, family target
groups because
our product is for families, and give human signals very strong, authenticity.
I told you,
this is extremely important. The big issue, oh, this is really, really nice.
Here it says,
this is where we need to be careful. Emile Emily has multiple historical
allegations and celebrity
disputes attached to her name. This includes relationship allegations,
accusations from
industry colleagues, all right, okay? So I will not present this as established
facts.
All right, you see, so there is a lot of,
there is a lot of good stuff, but also we actually found out the things that we
want
to find out, which is background check from the things that people could
believe she's not
trustworthy. This controversial history will make me, for example, don't not
prioritize her,
even if she seems to be a good celebrity, but this needs to be perfect if you
want to risk
to invest because this lady probably cost around, again, 50k to 100k. So this
is the first signal.
Let's go back to the drafting board. So we checked AI research with the happy
flops brain,
right? What we do next? Local interviews. What does it mean, local interviews?
So let's say we choose this, let's say we will do local interviews about this
Emily,
what does it mean? I will explain. And this is also, by the way, something that
we always do
here. We take around 50 people from UK, in this case, because this is a UK
celebrity,
and we ask about Emily here. Ask about Emily. The questions are, do you like
her? Like,
do you trust her? Would you buy from her if she recommends something?
Recommend. Do you respect her? Respect, right? Trust. Do you trust her? Do you
like her? Would you
buy from her? So the date that we get from these 50 people about Emily is very
important. I would
even say it's more important than the AI brain prompt that we will give you.
Even if the AI
is extremely intelligent now due to this training that we have done. But
sometimes there is a lot of
things that AI cannot catch online because it's the real information that is
out there, for example,
scandals that has not been published, but people know, for some reason,
things on TV that AI cannot really catch up or catch, capture. These things
will come from the
interview of 50 people. Extremely important. So we will get a score here, AI,
and we will also
get the score from the local interviews. Extremely, extremely important.
Why we also mention radio and journalist, guys? Very important lesson here. Why
do we believe or
why do this particular kind of celebrities generate a lot of trust and converts
a lot?
Because these three kinds of celebrities has been exposed on their personality,
at least what people believe. On TV, for example, people are used to see
the news guy every day, eight a.m. in the morning, or the news lady,
every day, eight a.m. in the morning, for years, for decades. And this is a
place in an environment
where they are exposing their personality. So they are creating connection with
the audience
because people are listening to them every day. The same with radio.
We have been working with so many radio hosts. And you know why this is working
so well? It's
the same because people are used to their voice. And obviously, not all the
radio hosts are perfect
or converts all the time. You need to understand the radio host from the radio
channel that people
love to listen, not music, not anything like that, but a radio channel that
people likes
because they like the person, right? This is the key. This is the gold mine
because people feel
like they know them here, like they know them. I will write this down and I
will
circle it around because it's the biggest lesson you need to understand. This
same with
journalists. Journalists are also on TV. They write stories. They are very
emotional. A lot of people
in our countries, they know a lot of journalists that have made a name for
themselves, right?
That stands for something. So with that for the set, let's go back to Modash
and let me show you how you could
search for this. So United Kingdom, we will put radio host
right and let's see how many we will get. In United Kingdom, we will get
40 profiles. So you will go through all 40, all of them, all of these radio
host people,
at least what it seems like. You will send this Instagram link to the happy fl
ops brain,
happy flops influencer technology brain. You will look through the whole report
,
right? As I thought you already and then you will get a score and you should
also remember
do the local people interviews from all the celebrities.
Great guys. This is the way you will make a list of celebrities. This is the
most intelligent way,
the most accurate way, the best and the most trusted way how to find
celebrities
worth investing in. It doesn't matter what you're selling as long as your
product is a product
that this celebrity can use. It doesn't need to be a perfect match. It only
needs to be a product
that they can use because that even makes this collaboration even more genuine.
Great. How do we do a list of high performing influencers? This is also a
little bit of
exploration you need to do. One of the things that I will recommend, even
though I've said
that it doesn't need to match product and influencer, but however you could try
to do
use keywords that is relatable to your brand. For example, what do I mean with
this?
Here, happy flops works with a lot of mom influencers. I will put mother
and then we will get 700 profiles, 753. So, I taught you guys, we want to do
approximately a list of 100 people to investigate in celebrities and also high
performing influencers.
We want to do from 100 to 200 influencers, we want to investigate. So, 700,
53 is too much. So, then we will look at amount of following. In this case, for
example, you can
also choose gender. In my case, as in happy flops, we are working a lot with
women influencers,
so I will put female and we will put followers starting from 100,000.
Here like this, perfect. You see, we filter it down. So, as high performing
influencers,
I will tell you a rule here. They don't need to be above 100,000, but it's good
to start there.
Usually, when you find high performing influencers, it's best to start
when they do have 100,000 followers and above. You should start to look there
because it means
that they usually, if you find high performing ones within that field, the good
ones, I mean,
then it means that they do have a certain level of experience. However, if you
look, for example,
through these 64 profiles and you don't find what we want to find, then you
will change this from,
for example, 50,000 up to 100,000. Let's see how many we get there, 50 profiles
. So,
basically, we got 60 profiles that has this keyword "mother" and that has 100,
000 followers
and above. And we also have 50 profiles that also writes "mother", but they
have below 100,000,
but it's between 50 to 100,000. You need to look at both of these, right? Both
of these. We got
now already a list of 100 or 110, approximately, right? This is the way you
should have the list of
top 100 and then you should go through it. Just go through it, go through it,
go through it. I will
teach you what you should look at. I will teach you this in a second step in
this chapter,
but now I'm teaching you just how to create a list. Let's go back to the
drafting board.
I also wrote here award winners. This is very easy. All right. You should just
have a chat with Chachippity, Uncle Chat or Claude or Google and you should
search for
influencer of the JIR UK, for example. Search and look if there is any awards,
any contest in
your country where you are looking this for and look for all the people that
has been winning
or won these awards. Don't look only for the award winner of last year. Look
for the three years,
the last three years. Usually, three years is a really good timeline because
these people that
who have won awards have made a really great social impact, right? And they
have been voted
to win. And this is really good. And I see this pattern. Look, this is not what
I think. This is
not what I believe. This is a pattern that we found out after doing this for
five years.
When we launched a new country, this is the first thing we do as well. We look
for the award winners
and there is always different categories in these award winners as well. Look
through all of them,
all right? Good, guys. Perfect. I taught you how to make a celebrity list good.
And now I also
taught you how to do a high performing influencer list good enough. You should
play around with the
words. For example, if you sell something within makeup, maybe you should write
a look for maybe
makeup artist, you know, and let's see what we can find. You see, seven
profiles or stylist,
you know, you should be creative and see what you can find.
And what I try to teach you here is that you should use this bio to think in a
way what you think
your target group influencer would write on their bio. Think about that. Ask
you that that,
ask you this question to yourself and then try some different keywords, all
right?
Perfect, guys. Now let's go to the next chapter, which is how do we measure
this?
Guys, we have come to probably the most important part of these looms, which is
, okay, now we have
the list for celebrities, we have the list for influencers. How the heck do we
choose 10 from
this 100, right? This is the biggest, most difficult task. Which 10 celebrities
is worth to
investigate or invest in? Which 10 influencers do we invest in? Now, guys, look
,
I try to make it easy to understand by a really, really short summary,
celebrities trust is equal
to respect, like admired by 9 out of 10 local people. Perfect. And trust for
high performing
influencers is equal to stories, comments and relationship building. Now, let
me show you what
I mean with this, all right? I mean, with celebrities, we already understand
how to do this, you know,
we do the local interviews, at least 50 people, all right? Do 100 if you can.
Perfect.
How to do it? Find your way. We have multiple ways how to do it. We do service,
we do contact
communities, we do everything, everything that comes in mind. We just try to
reach 50 people
in a group or one by one, and we find out these answers. Now, how do we, when
we have a list,
this is what you want to see. Let me show you. This is what you want to see.
This is just an
example, okay? So, when you're looking through the list of your influencer and
you will do this
human observation, you will need to do this. This is what you want to find.
I couldn't talk at the same time because you wouldn't listen. This is a person
that is
communicating with her with her audience. She's not wearing makeup. She's not
caring about any fancy
glamorous lifestyle. She's just being real. She's being raw. She's stalking.
She's speaking to her
audience, all right? This is what you will and what you are searching for. This
is how we measure trust.
Look, if you find a profile that does this kind of stories every day, at least
for a whole week,
you found it. You found the golden mind. You found exactly what we at Happy Pl
ops are looking for as
well, all right? And this is really hard to find. And I can promise you, when
you look, when you go
through 100 influencers, you maybe will find two. You maybe will find five.
Maybe if you're lucky,
you find 10, all right? But it's really hard. But this is it, guys. This is
exactly what you want.
You want to find profiles that are personal and relatable to their audience,
that are genuine, authentic, and that has a relationship with their audience,
right?
Another way how to do this on her pose, for example. You see that she does
personal pose. She's
she's publicly with her husband, with kids. She's not showing a perfect life.
She's being very authentic.
She's being very real. Not everything is perfect. This is also what you want to
see in her pose.
Not you want to see a human being, right? Look, look how much she's talking.
So this profile is one of the examples. Let's go through some more.
Look at this. We are uploading. Look at this. Look at this. You know why this
is beautiful?
Because look how much she is talking in front of the camera. Here,
talking, talking, talking, talking, talking, talking. So obviously, not because
only you're
talking, it means that you are you have the biggest trust of them all. It
obviously depends
what you're talking about. It obviously depends if by the things that you are
talking that you're
gaining trust. And this is also something you need to measure. If she's having
this microphone
and she's talking shit. The world is shit. Life is shit. And everything is shit
. Obviously,
maybe people wouldn't like her. But in this case, we listen. We listen. What is
she saying?
What is she talking about? She's talking about families. She's talking about
personal struggles.
She's talking about beautiful things in life. She's talking about, she's
vulnerable things.
That is trust. And look, stories again.
So for example, now we are looking at posts that are very much way more normal,
like any other
influencer. But normally, this influencer, which is just talking, talking,
talking exactly as the
one that we were looking at recently. Let's see another one, just as an example
. You see here,
this is people that are just communicating a lot with their, this is also a
really popular one.
You are writing long texts on stories, long texts on stories, personal texts,
opening up. This is also like the closest you can get to just talking on the
camera.
I don't know about you guys, but when you see these kinds of stories, you get
the chance
to know the person. You get the chance to understand who they are, right? And
then that chance might
convert to trust or to the opposite of trust, right? They could be speaking
about really bad
things that you don't like, of course. But now we are focusing on finding the
people that are
talking about good things, that is opening up to their audiences, that people
like, that people
find admirationable or inspirational to listen to. This is what converts
because it's trust behind,
all right? I challenge you guys to go out and hunt like we do. We have a
department and a team of 10
people looking for these profiles. And they are out there in every country,
they are out there,
but they're really rare and they are really, really hard to find. But when you
find these,
oh guys, I can promise you, you can invest and invest and you will find the
best,
best return in your life because you find ambassadors that people trust and you
will get your brand
trusted by doing this, all right? This is why influencer marketing is very hard
because it's
really hard to find these people. Let's see if we have another example. I would
say maybe this one.
You see, this is also typical long text, a photo of yourself without makeup.
This is perfect.
This is what we want to find. Personal stuff, personal stuff, openingness,
because it creates
relationship. Good. So all the influencers that I showed you are influencers
that I know for a fact
has been selling for a lot, a lot of money. But whatever you are in US, in
Europe, in Latin America,
or whatever, this strategy is always the same. And this is exactly what you
should look for and
find. This is how we measure trust, all right? One human observations. We don't
check these stories
for one day. No. We check these for two weeks. We check if the influencers are
consistent in this
behavior. We check if they are publishing like this at least every day for two
weeks, all right?
It doesn't need to be 50 stories every day, right? But it needs to be a lot of
stories every day.
We see this. This is the pattern, guys. I told you, we've had tens of tens of
influencers that
have been selling basically approximately around 50 million dollars USD for us
influencers. And
all of these influencers has exactly this in common, all right? So this is no
theory. This is no
bullshit belief. This is facts. We've seen this, we've proven it in different
countries with different
brands, always, always the same. Finally, we found out this is it. And it's not
strange that it's hard
to find because as you already see, not a lot of influencers are doing this. So
if you are an
influencer, by the way, and you're listening to this, this is what you should
do. And obviously,
it's hard. It's not easy to pick up the phone and start talking to the camera
every day.
That's not easy. I can tell you this. I've tried. I've tried myself. It's not
easy. It's very
consuming. And also, you have to have a level of caringness for the audience,
which is also very
rare. A lot of people just want to be famous. Recognition, validation. But not
a lot of people
care about their audience. And the people who are talking to their audience
every day like this
is because they have another level of caring. They care about communicating
with them and
bond with them and create a relationship with them. All right, guys?
Now, let's move towards how do we also see this in Modash? All right, how do we
see this in Modash?
Now, let's go to the next. Let me see what the name of this influencer. I
wanted to show you
how we will clear this. I want to show you how you also will find the good
signals,
the metrics that you should care about when you're looking and are evaluating
and are measuring
the potential of the influencer. So, we look for the profile here in Creator.
We will find, you will click on view profile and then you will open full report
.
And now, I will show you basically this. I will actually download this PDF. Let
me see.
I will save this. I actually want to copy this. Good.
Let's see if we can add this here. Paste it here. Can we? Yes, here, I think.
Well, I feel no. How do we do this? Guys, here. No. No, no, no, no, no.
So look, we do this.
Okay, now, you will learn some Swedish now. Now, we have it here. We should
have it here. We should
have it here. Yes, perfect. Perfect, perfect, perfect. Because I would love to
show you what is
important here. All right, all right, guys, here we go to some very important
things.
So, this influencer has really nice modash numbers. We call it in our company,
we call it modash
numbers. So, when we take decisions, we look at two things. One, modash numbers
. And two,
human observation for two weeks, as I told you guys, two weeks. I would say 70%
of the decision
lies here in the human observation and 30% here. So, modash is really good to
have, to kind of
understand the signals. And what signals? Because modash gives you a lot of
stuff. This is not even
everything, actually. Can I write it? Yeah, I can. Perfect. First of all, we
don't look at this.
We don't care. What do we care about them? Look, guys, when we analyzed all the
people that
has been selling for us for tens of millions of dollars, they all of them have
below 15%
of fake followers. Always less, all right? And you could look for any influ
encer. You would see
how normal it is to have 30, 40%. This is like the normal. This is normal. What
is not normal?
11. This is great. Amazing signal. Even more if she has one million followers.
Insane.
And I know this influencer is converting a lot. I know this. So, that's also
why I show you this.
The next metric we look at is real people. Modash has this metric where they
are
basically showing you how big percentage of the audience, in this case 82%,
is actually behaving like human beings. You understand? Modash gives you a real
people rate.
Like 82% of her audience seems to be real. Real people, not robots, not
algorithms,
not fake, all right? And this is also really rare. Normal, this is normal to be
here.
This is normal. To have it to 82%, super good signal. Amazing signal. And I
would say 75,
to 90, usually all the best influencers that we have always have around this 75
to 90%.
30 counts or less. This means that 70% of her audience follows only 500
accounts or less.
This is also good because it means that her followers really wants to follow
her. They're not
following like multiple thousands of people, which is then called mass
following. Also good,
and also by the way, the normal is here. A lot of influencers has like 20% here
. Only 20% of
their audience is following 500 accounts or less. This is the pattern, guys. I
'm telling you all
the best influencers you can look through when you find the guts to invest. And
you will see that
it converts. I can promise you that they will match this exact metrics. They
will have this.
They will have 80% here. They will have 70% here. They will have around 10% or
15% here.
It's always the same. It's the pattern. This is how we measure it. If the fake
follower rate is
40%, 30%, we don't usually do so much like more checking actually, right? But
we look for the
signals. We look for this is how we measure. What else is important? Average
comments.
Do you know what my golden rule is in average comments? I've looked at all of
the best
influencers that has been selling millions, millions of dollars for us. And all
of them have
at least minimum of average of 60 comments on every post. This woman has 145.
This is insane.
This is really good signal. If there is less, for example, 20 or 30, usually
means
she is not posting significant enough posts. When you have at least 60 comments
on average,
it means that people are really relating, like they're really communicating
back with this person.
They are commenting. They are making questions. And this is also important
because comments
is a relationship factor because they're communicating. They're talking to each
other. The audience is
responding. And we found out that 60 on average is what everyone, all of the
best influencers that
we have used ever has 60. What else? Pays engagement is also a metric we look
at sometimes.
For example, in this case, it doesn't seem good, but also it's like very, very
less important.
This means that her paid post, for example, if she's publishing a post about a
collaboration,
she gets 30% equal engagement as any normal post. Sometimes it's nice to have
it here,
like, for example, 80%. But yeah, we also see that this can vary a lot. For
example,
I know this influencer is insanely good. She sells for millions as well. And
yeah,
she has this 30% here. So this rate is less important, but we look at this
sometimes as well.
Sometimes we also look at a lot is the female rate. It's always around 80%. For
us, because our buyers
are females, so we need always to have this around 80% females. If this profile
would have like 50%
females, then we know that, yeah, a lot of men are following up for some other
kind of reasons.
And that is also telling us something, right? And then the age. Look, the
golden age for us,
and I think for a lot of you guys as well is here. The audience should be here
at this age,
the majority of them. We've tested so much to invest in this age. And I don't
know
probably because they have less purchasing power because they have less money.
It always
has been influencers that converts way less, way less. So we are always looking
for this,
the majority of the following age should be here over 25 years. It's really
good metric
to look at. And also, the last thing that I would like to show you is which
countries,
which country is the dominating audience base? If you are going to do
collaboration with an
influencer in the UK, then the majority of the audience should be in the UK. In
this case,
for example, this is a German influencer, so she should have majority in
Germany, so this is correct.
This is a good number because sometimes influencers are very spread, which
means that they are not
focusing on this country, which means very high risk if the audience is spread.
Good guys,
this is what we look for in Modash. It's not everything. This is like the
things that we look
for. Once we started to look at more things, we always mess it up. And I told
you this,
this is exactly the metric that we look at as well. Amazing, guys, this is how
you measure
the risk. And I hope that you really got it. I know this video is a little bit
long,
but I really want you to understand. This is basically the extra mile. All
right, I promise you,
if once you go out there and search for these things, you will invest so much
time into this
because it's hard. But this is what makes this great, because not a lot of
people know about this.
And also, there is no way people would believe this if they wouldn't have our
data,
if they wouldn't have our results, because we do have the results and the
experience and
five years behind us, so we know what we're talking about. And that's also why
we love this,
because this is what I'm showing you right now. This is not normal. And I
promise you,
I can almost guarantee there is almost no brand that they are doing research
like this.
This is the secret. This is the sweet of how to find winning high performing
influencers.
And it's hard. And it's time consuming. And this means we go the extra mile. Go
extra mile.
When you go the extra mile, life rewards you. And this is it guys. So thank you
for watching this
chapter. I hope that you really understood the concept. I hope that you liked
it. I hope it
makes sense for you. I wish you the best of luck when you go out and hunt for
some amazing influencers
in whatever country that you are planning to look.